Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is set up a dash system.
So I'll play a character.
We'll be able to dash in any direction.
To get started, let's set up the button that my play character is going to have to press in order to
dash.
If we go to edit and project settings.
And just go to input.
Let's go to action mapping and create a new action mapping and just call this dash.
And I'm going to make that simple when I press the Z on my placard to Will Dash.
So we can just close this and head back to our plan blueprint.
Okay.
So with this project, before we continue, because I don't want things to get too messy, I'm going
to common all my nodes, so I'm just going to select all these nodes here and then press C.
This will be a common around them and I'm just going to call this jump.
So here I know that all these nodes handle the jumping for my pair character.
I'm going to copy all these nodes and I'm going to call this handle movement.
And I'll just move it up here.
I'm going to commit all these notes and call the scandal rotation.
So now everything's just a bit more organized.
So we're going to set up all happen with my character dashes.
So in some free space, I'm just going to right click and look for Dash.
I'm going to select Action Event Dash.
So when I press the dashboard first, we're going to look for the do once.
And the way this mode works is it will only file once unless we have a reset.
Then we're going to launch our character.
And we're going to launch them in the x axis.
So just right click on here.
And the force bit structure pin.
So we need to know whether we're going to launch our character positively in the x axis or negatively
in the x axis.
So we can do that by dragging in our right variable, because this will tell us if our character is
facing towards the right or left.
And we can just drag up here and look for select.
And go down humans like this one with the three little arrows and pick up from the return value into
x.
And we can see that as a false and a true.
So.
Under true.
We want this to be a positive value, but something like 3000 and under false, you want this to be
a negative value.
Make this -3000.
And I go from completed into here.
So the idea here is when we press the dashboard, we to launch our character.
If they're moving towards the right, we're going to launch them positively 3000 units in the x axis.
If they're moving towards the left, then we're going to launch them -3000 units in the x axis.
And then we're asked to click this Z override and the Z override.
What checking these boxes will do is will make it so that our player character's velocity will match
all of these values.
If these values were unchecked, what would happen when I launch the character is it will just add this
velocity onto my character's current x velocity.
I want it to replace my character's velocity with these values.
So just make sure that these are both checked.
So after we launch up our character, I'm going to have a delay.
So I'm just going to drag up here for delay.
And I'm going to have a delay of 0.3 seconds.
And then I will hook from completed into this reset.
Then just double click.
Just so that it's a bit cleaner.
And I also double click here just as a bit cleaner to see what's happening.
So when I press the dashboard, I'm going to call the do once node so I can do it once all my character,
depending whether they're facing towards the right or left.
Then we have a delay of 0.3 seconds and that will reset my view once.
So I'm only going to be up to dash every 0.3 seconds.
Let's compile and test that.
Everything works.
So let's close this, go play, proceed and we can see it dashes my character towards the right and
I'm facing towards the right.
If I turn around and press C dash my character towards the left.
There's one problem with our current dash system.
If I was to jump in there and then we can see it looks kind of weird and really off.
So the first reason it looks off is because there's no friction being applied to us when we're dashing
in the air.
To fix that, we can go to our player VP and go to character movement.
And under here we're going to look for lateral friction.
We currently are fooling lateral friction and zero, which means there is no friction applied when repair
character is falling through the air.
We want this to be a value of 2.5.
I found that works well, so the higher this value, the stronger the friction is going to be.
Just compile and go save.
Now, when I try to dash, when I'm in there, it's not going to be as strong because there's going
to be some friction applied to me.
I also made my back out to jump pretty high, so I'm just going to change his jump value.
Back to.
I think the default is 400.
Just so it looks a bit.
Better to see so I can jump.
And that.
There's actually one more thing I want to fix with my dating system so I can play it if I jump and dash
whilst I'm in the air.
You may be able to notice my character starts to slowly fall towards the ground as they're dashing.
I want it to go when my player character is dashing in the air.
They don't fall towards the ground.
So in order to set up that fact, when my player character presents the dashboard, I'm going to check
to see whether the in the air.
We can do that by dragging in character movement, dragging off here and look for it's falling.
I'm just going to select and move these nodes back a bit.
If my character is falling, that means that in the air.
So that's a trick up here.
And look for Branch.
If my character is in the air, the one will do is drag in my character movement and drag and set gravity
scale.
And also the gravity scale to be there.
That basically means my character is just going to float in the air.
Then I'm going to launch my character after these 0.3 seconds.
I'm going to set the gravity scale back to its normal level.
So I just let my character movement and look for gravity.
The default gravity scale is one.
I'm just going to leave out this value.
So after the 1.3 seconds, after I've launched my character and I set the gravity scale back to be one.
So I'm going to copy the node here and put one here.
And just hop from completed now to here and from here to here.
I'm just going to track this note up a bit so it's a bit cleaner.
And of course, we just want to hook to North character.
So only if my character is in the air when the dashing will set that gravity to be zero.
So now I can go compile, close this and go play.
Bypass baseball and proceed.
My character will not be falling when that dashing.
In the next lecture, we'll set up how to implement the dating animation.